<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTTPS on Today in Sisk</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/https/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTTPS on Today in Sisk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/https/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cadente on the edge: running Sisk without the old seatbelts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-11-14-cadente-on-the-edge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-11-14-cadente-on-the-edge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending the last weeks almost exclusively inside Wireshark traces and benchmark charts, and I can finally say this out loud: the &lt;strong&gt;Cadente project is almost ready&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not &amp;ldquo;marketing ready&amp;rdquo;. I mean &amp;ldquo;I can run Sisk on it without being terrified every five minutes&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cadente, if you missed the earlier post, is that bold attempt to write a &lt;strong&gt;pure C# HTTP/1.1 + SSL server engine&lt;/strong&gt; for Sisk – basically, a Kestrel‑like role in the Sisk ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TechEmpower benchmark results are out!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-02-18-techempower-results-are-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-02-18-techempower-results-are-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My goal was never to lie about Sisk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I understood its limitations and problems, and worked to resolve and improve it. Some commercial projects already work well with Sisk, have pleasant performance, and are easy to maintain because they are open-source.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I discovered that the HttpListener interface was very slow on Linux servers. On Windows, it is very fast, and even supports QUIC, but it depends on Windows. On Linux servers, which make up 99% of servers out there, there was an extra layer of having to use a proxy to handle SSL traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cadente: a bold experiment for Sisk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-29-cadente-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2025-01-29-cadente-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You must have noticed that the SslProxy project has stopped. And yes, indeed, it will be discontinued soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But this does not mean that its initial purpose has ceased to exist: bringing native HTTPS to Sisk. In fact, the project has taken a new direction, which led to the construction of the Cadente project: a pure C# implementation of HTTP/1.1 with SSL support, which should soon be implemented in Sisk/Core.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed up Sisk using streams</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-14-speed-up-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 02:56:51 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-14-speed-up-streams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading and writing content with HTTP seems simple? With C#, it&amp;rsquo;s even easier. But are you doing it the right way?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If I asked you to serve an image through the &lt;code&gt;GET /cute-dog.png&lt;/code&gt; route, how would you do it? Well, the simplest way would be to read the file, get its content type, and send it in the response. Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/CypherPotato/0286e6af1bc6012070d4d3ef009f3a45.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you see any problem in the code above? If I open my browser and access &lt;code&gt;https://localhost:8080/cute-dog.png&lt;/code&gt;, this would be the result:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTTPS is coming, natively, to Sisk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-10-ssliscoming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 20:33:48 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-09-10-ssliscoming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly it. I am working on my own implementation of an HTTP/1.1 serializer with HTTPS support for Sisk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I received new personnel to join the team where I work. This new team took on a project that is running with Sisk alongside me. It is a large, high-complexity project, and I was proud to present Sisk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While showing them the project, I had to teach them how to get it working. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t like a conventional project; Sisk required a much larger, tedious, and discouraging initial setup. The reason for this was SSL. Our project depended on cookie-based authentication across domains, and these were domains mapped to the computer&amp;rsquo;s localhost (the so-called &lt;code&gt;hosts&lt;/code&gt; file). This setup involved:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
